<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Silvia D&#39;Angelo</title>
    <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Silvia D&#39;Angelo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://silviadangelo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio-Intake web application</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/biointake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/biointake/</guid>
      <description>Bio-Intake (Biomarker guided dietary intake) allows users to upload mean daily self-reported citrus intake data (g/day) (estimated from food diaries) and computes calibrated intakes (g/day) based on a biomarker calibration equation. The biomarker based calibration equation was developed from urinary proline betaine and mean daily intake (estimated from a 4 day food diary) and is used to correct self-report estimates for measurement error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multiMarker R package</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/multimarker_cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/multimarker_cran/</guid>
      <description>A latent variable model based on factor analytic and mixture of experts models, designed to infer food intake from multiple biomarkers data. The model is framed within a Bayesian hierarchical framework, which provides flexibility to adapt to different biomarker distributions and facilitates inference on food intake from biomarker data alone, along with the associated uncertainty. Details are in D&#39;Angelo, et al. (2020) arXiv:2006.02995.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multiMarker web application</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/multimarker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/multimarker/</guid>
      <description>multiMarker is a web application that infers the relationship between biomarker and food quantity data from an intervention study, and allows prediction of food intake when only biomarker data are available. Additionally, multiMarker provides quantification of the uncertainty in intake predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spaceNet R package</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/spacenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/spacenet/</guid>
      <description>Latent space models for multivariate networks (multiplex) estimated via MCMC algorithm. See D Angelo et al. (2018) arXiv:1803.07166 and D Angelo et al. (2018) arXiv:1807.03874.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model-based clustering for multidimensional social networks.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/clust_net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/clust_net/</guid>
      <description>Silvia D’Angelo, Marco Alfo&amp;rsquo;, and Michael Fop (2023).
Journal of the Royal Statistical Society Series A: Statistics in Society.
Social network data are relational data recorded among a group of actors, interacting in different contexts. Often, the same set of actors can be characterised by multiple social relations, captured by a multidimensional network. A common situation is that of colleagues working in the same institution, whose social interactions can be defined on professional and personal levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining biomarker and food intake data.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/wiley_stat_ref/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/wiley_stat_ref/</guid>
      <description>Isobel Claire Gormley, Silvia D’Angelo, and Lorraine Brennan (2022).
Wiley StatsRef - Statistics Reference Online.
Recent developments in biomarker discovery have demonstrated that combining biomarkers with self-reported intake data has the potential to improve estimation of food intake. Here, statistical methods for combining biomarker and self-reported food intake data are discussed. The calibration equations method is a widely applied method that corrects for measurement error in self-reported food intake data through the use of biomarker data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inferring food intake from multiple biomarkers using a latent variable model.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/annals_multimarker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/annals_multimarker/</guid>
      <description>Silvia D’Angelo, Lorraine Brennan, and Isobel Claire Gormley (2021).
Annals of Applied Statistics.
Metabolomic-based approaches have gained much attention in recent years, due to their promising potential to deliver objective tools for assessment of food intake. In particular, multiple biomarkers have emerged for single foods. However, there is a lack of statistical tools available for combining multiple biomarkers to quantitatively infer food intake. Furthermore, there is a paucity of approaches for estimating the uncertainty around biomarker-based inferred intake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multiMarker : software for modelling and prediction of continuous food intake using multiple biomarker measurements.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/bmcbio_multimarker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/bmcbio_multimarker/</guid>
      <description>Silvia D’Angelo, Isobel Claire Gormley, Aoife E. McNamara, and Lorraine Brennan (2021).
BMC Bioinformatics.
Background Metabolomic biomarkers offer potential for objective and reliable food intake assessment, and there is growing interest in using biomarkers in place of or with traditional self-reported approaches. Ongoing research suggests that multiple biomarkers are associated with single foods, offering great sensitivity and specificity. However, currently there is a dearth of methods to model the relationship between multiple biomarkers and single food intake measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling node heterogeneity in latent space models for multidimensional networks.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/statneer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/statneer/</guid>
      <description>D&#39;Angelo,S., Alfò, M. and Murphy, T.B. (2020).
Statistica Neerlandica.
Multidimensional network data can have different levels of complexity, as nodes may be characterized by heterogeneous individual‐specific features, which may vary across the networks. This article introduces a class of models for multidimensional network data, where different levels of heterogeneity within and between networks can be considered. The proposed framework is developed in the family of latent space models, and it aims to distinguish symmetric relations between the nodes and node‐specific features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining biomarker and food intake data: calibration equations for citrus intake.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/ajcn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/ajcn/</guid>
      <description>D’Angelo, S., Gormley, I.C., McNulty, B.A., Nugent, A.P., Walton, J., Flynn, A. and Brennan, L. (2019).
American Journal of Clinical Nutrition.
Measurement error associated with self-reported dietary intake is a well-documented issue. Combining biomarkers of food intake and dietary intake data is a high priority. The aim of this study was to develop calibration equations for food intake, illustrated with an application for citrus intake. Further, a simulation-based framework was developed to determine the portion of biomarker data needed for stable calibration equation estimation in large population studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latent space modeling of multidimensional networks with application to the exchange of votes in the Eurovision Song Contest.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/eurovision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/eurovision/</guid>
      <description>D’Angelo, S., Murphy, T.B. and Alfò, M. (2019).
Annals of Applied Statistics.
The Eurovision Song Contest is a popular TV singing competition held annually among country members of the European Broadcasting Union. In this competition, each member can be both contestant and jury, as it can participate with a song and/or vote for other countries&amp;rsquo; tunes. During the years, the voting system has repeatedly been accused of being biased by tactical voting; votes would represent strategic interests rather than actual musical preferences of the voting countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A network approach to studying cause-of-death interrelations.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/demo/</guid>
      <description>Rivellini, G., Salvatore, M.A., Egidi, V. and D’Angelo, S. (2018).
Demographic Research.
Multiple causes of death describe complex death processes marked by the simultaneous presence of several diseases and conditions, primarily at older ages. We intend to explore the opportunity offered by the Social Network Analysis (SNA) in the study of multiple relationships in the causes of death. SNA allowed us to reconstruct the complex system of relationships linking the causes of death mentioned in the same death certificate for Italian men and women aged 65 years and over in 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding dependency patterns in structural and functional brain connectivity through fMRI and DTI data.</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/suresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/publications/suresearch/</guid>
      <description>Crispino, M., D’Angelo, S., Ranciati, S., and Mira, A. (2018).
Contributions to Neural Data Science, proceedings of Startup Research, Springer Proceedings in Mathematics and Statistics.
Neuroscience and neuroimaging have been providing new challenges for statisticians and quantitative researchers in general. As datasets of increasing complexity and dimension become available, the need for statistical techniques to analyze brain related phenomena becomes prominent. In this paper, we delve into data coming from functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) and Diffusion Tensor Imaging (DTI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BOSH release for Bamboo &amp; Remote Agents</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/creations/bosh-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/creations/bosh-agents/</guid>
      <description>BOSH (Bosh Outer SHell) &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;is an open source tool for release engineering, deployment, lifecycle management, and monitoring of distributed systems.&amp;rdquo; And it&#39;s amazingly powerful. This examples uses BOSH to provision an Alassian vendor app running on JDK along with the support Postgres database and agents to support it. The releases manages the health of services and will automatically provision, start/stop processes across the various services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&#39;t matter whether it&#39;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
 First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;rdquo; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian Marketplace Plugins</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/creations/marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/creations/marketplace/</guid>
      <description>Multiple plugins used by thousands of teams that provide enhanced functionality of Atlassian’s core products (primarily JIRA and Bamboo) to enrich CI/CD capabilities, DevOps automation, or productivity. Functionality spans user interface, web services and persistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker image for Bitbucket CI/CD Pipelines  &#34;shipit&#34;</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/creations/docker-marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/creations/docker-marketplace/</guid>
      <description>Provides required dependencies and additional utilities to simplify and codify the process of building, testing and delivering Atlassian plugins all the way to the live marketplace.Executes integration/AUT level tests against all stated compatible versions for the productUploads generated artifact to Atlassian marketplaceProvides corresponding metadata indicating version, release notes, and compatibility</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>