<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open source software on Silvia D&#39;Angelo</title>
    <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open source software on Silvia D&#39;Angelo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio-Intake web application</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/biointake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/biointake/</guid>
      <description>Bio-Intake (Biomarker guided dietary intake) allows users to upload mean daily self-reported citrus intake data (g/day) (estimated from food diaries) and computes calibrated intakes (g/day) based on a biomarker calibration equation. The biomarker based calibration equation was developed from urinary proline betaine and mean daily intake (estimated from a 4 day food diary) and is used to correct self-report estimates for measurement error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multiMarker R package</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/multimarker_cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/multimarker_cran/</guid>
      <description>A latent variable model based on factor analytic and mixture of experts models, designed to infer food intake from multiple biomarkers data. The model is framed within a Bayesian hierarchical framework, which provides flexibility to adapt to different biomarker distributions and facilitates inference on food intake from biomarker data alone, along with the associated uncertainty. Details are in D&#39;Angelo, et al. (2020) arXiv:2006.02995.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multiMarker web application</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/multimarker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/multimarker/</guid>
      <description>multiMarker is a web application that infers the relationship between biomarker and food quantity data from an intervention study, and allows prediction of food intake when only biomarker data are available. Additionally, multiMarker provides quantification of the uncertainty in intake predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spaceNet R package</title>
      <link>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/spacenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://silviadangelo.github.io/projects/contributions/spacenet/</guid>
      <description>Latent space models for multivariate networks (multiplex) estimated via MCMC algorithm. See D Angelo et al. (2018) arXiv:1803.07166 and D Angelo et al. (2018) arXiv:1807.03874.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>